Guide to the A. B. Cook Papers 1882-1940
Montana Historical Society Archives
- A.B. Cook
  - General Correspondence
    - Wallace's Farmer (Henry C. Wallace, Des Moines, Iowa), 1920 (Box-folder 18 / 29)
    - James A. Walsh (Helena, Mont.), 1918-1921 (Box-folder 18 / 30)
    - Thomas J. Walsh (U.S. Senator), 1914-1927 (Box-folder 18 / 31)
    - Walters Brothers, Walters Company, C.N. Walters and Son (Buffalo, Wyo.), 1919-1928 (Box-folder 18 / 32)
    - Ernest L. Walton (Bainville, Mont.), 1927 (Box-folder 18 / 33)
    - Carlos Warfield (Toronto, Ont., also includes Marion Warfield; see also Hygeia Ice Company), 1912-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 18 / 34-35)
    - M.R. Warnick (Middle West Farm, Leola, S.D.), 1922-1923 (Box-folder 18 / 36)
    - J.D. Watson (includes Knight-Watson Ranching Company, Lethbridge, Alta.), 1912-1928 (Box-folder 18 / 37-38)
    - Alex Watt (Kilherran, B.C.), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 19 / 1)
    - George Watterson (Bishop, Calif.), 1921-1922 (Box-folder 19 / 2)
    - Wa (correspondents include Alex Wagstaff, Waite Brothers and Company, Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, Walkers' Cash Liquor House, D.D. Walker, J.M. Walker, Herbert Wall, Edgar T. Wallace, John Walsh, Frank Ward, R.M. Washington, Washington State Fair, Waterloo Cement Machinery Company, E.C. Waters, James E. Watson, Luella E. Watson), 1907-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 3)
    - C.C. Webber (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1922-1927 (Box-folder 19 / 4)
    - John V. Weber (Clancy, Mont.), 1918-1924 (Box-folder 19 / 5)
    - F.A. Weinrich (Fort Union, Mont.), 1925-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 6)
    - Wentworth Realties Ltd. (John Findlay, Montreal, Que.; includes financial statement), 1924-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 7)
    - Western Empire Insurance Company (includes financial statements, etc.), 1909-1915 (Box-folder 19 / 8)
    - Western Engineering Company (includes legal documents), 1909-1911 (Box-folder 19 / 9)
    - Western Hereford Breeders Association (includes John Painter, T.F. DeWitt), 1915-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 10)
    - Western Seed Company (Denver, Colo.), 1920-1923 (Box-folder 19 / 11)
    - Western States Land and Development Company (Helena, Mont.), 1917 (Box-folder 19 / 12)
    - Western (correspondents include Western Auto and Supply Company, Western Breeders Journal, Western Contract Company, Western Royal Live Stock Association), 1912-1927 (Box-folder 19 / 13)
    - Weston Manufacturing and Supply Company (Denver, Colo.), 1918-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 14)
    - We (correspondents include Elbert D. Weed, John B. Emily Wellcome, G.W. Wermersen, West End Factory, A.O. Westberg, Martin Westland, R.G. Weston), 1906-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 15)
    - D.J. Whaley (Missoula, Mont.), 1908 (Box-folder 19 / 16)
    - J.C. Whaley (Montana Ditch Company, Townsend, Mont.), 1918 (Box-folder 19 / 17)
    - Burton K. Wheeler (United States Senator), 1924-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 18)
    - Charles W. Whitcomb (includes report on Ruby Gulch gold property, Little Rockies), 1910-1920 (Box-folder 19 / 19)
    - White Holland Turkeys, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 20)
    - White (correspondents include B.F. White, White Bear Golf and Yacht Club, White Brothers, L.C. White, W. McC. White inclosing prospectus for Butte and Vipond Gold Mining and Milling Company), 1909-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 21)
    - Fred Whiteside (includes reports on Lodge Grass oil structure and on St. Andrews Bay Tract, Florida) [map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 1], 1928 (Box-folder 19 / 22)
    - Wh (correspondents include Fred J. Whitcroft, W.C. Whipps, M.C. Whitegaard), 1912-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 23)
    - W.F. Wilkins (Compania Ganadera de Atotonileo, Mexico), 1926-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 24)
    - A.R. Williams (Moorhead, Mont.), 1921-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 25)
    - George L. Williams (White Sulphur Springs, Mont.), 1916-1918 (Box-folder 19 / 26)
    - Williams (correspondents include A.G. Williams, C.H. Williams, W.H. Williams), 1916-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 27)
    - Williamson (correspondents include C.O. Williamson, Stewart Williamson), 1917-1922 (Box-folder 19 / 28)
    - Wilson (correspondents include F.D. Wilson, George A. Wilson, John R. Wilson, Lark Wilson), 1921-1926 (Box-folder 19 / 29)
    - Winnecook Ranch Company (Winnecook, Mont.), 1923-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 30)
    - Lawrence M. Winters (Saskatoon, Sask.), 1921 (Box-folder 19 / 31)
    - Hiram S. Winterton (Winterton Brothers, Charleston, Utah), 1918-1926 (Box-folder 19 / 32)
    - W.W. Withie (Buenes Aires, Argentina; Vancouver, B.C.), 1911-1912 (Box-folder 19 / 33)
    - Wi (correspondents include W.H. Wickens, R.A. Wigmore, Charles Wiley, Wilkie and Sellery Tailors, Wilkinson and Carroll Cotton Company, John Willis, J.M. Willis Cotton Products Company, E.A. Winstanley), 1907-1928 (Box-folder 19 / 34)
    - Wood Brothers Livestock Commission Merchants (Chicago, Ill.), 1908-1926 (Box-folder 20 / 1)
    - P.W. Woods (Helena, Mont.), 1918-1928 (Box-folder 20 / 2)
    - Wo (correspondents include Martin Woldson, Women's Directory of Montreal, Mark J. Woodhull, Wool Growers Marketing Company, Lester P. Work), 1914-1928 (Box-folder 20 / 3)
    - Wyoming State Fair, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 20 / 4)
    - Wr-Wy (correspondents include Thomas F. Wren, Al Wright, Lewis T. Wright, Will Wright, Writers Press Association, G.C. Wunn, Wyatt Live Stock Company, D.J. Wylie), 1918-1924 (Box-folder 20 / 5)
    - Y (correspondents include Yamsay Land and Cattle Company, Dan Yancey, Dave Yandall, Yellowstone National Park, Yellowstone Packing Company, Yellowstone Registered Livestock Association, L.L. Young, Young Men's Christian Association [YMCA]), 1907-1928 (Box-folder 20 / 6)
    - Zenoleum Products Company (Detroit, Mich.), 1926-1928 (Box-folder 20 / 7)
    - Z (correspondents include Ziemer's Poultry and Bee Farm, Henry Zimmer, Louis Zimmerman, Mose Zimmerman, George Zinec, unidentified), 1910-1925 (Box-folder 20 / 8)
    - Miscellaneous (re planned re-incorporation or sale of ranch, Hereford cattle sale), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 20 / 9)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book: personal, 1889-1891 (Box-folder 20 / 10)
    - Letterpress book: personal (re campaign for State Auditor), 1892 (Box-folder 20 / 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Letters of recommendation for A.B. Cook, 1882-1885 (Box-folder 20 / 12)
    - Letters of endorsement for A.B. Cook as U.S. Surveyor General for Montana, 1902 (Box-folder 20 / 13)
  - Court Papers
    - Butte and Boston Consolidated Mining Company vs. Montana Ore Purchasing Company et al. (includes assignments of fines to A.B. Cook; S.B. 5647 "for the relief of Andrew B. Cook, assignee"), 1908 (Box-folder 20 / 14)
    - A.B. Cook vs. John MacGinnis (includes brief of appellant; transcript on appeal), 1924 (Box-folder 20 / 15-16)
    - Amelia McStravick vs. A.B. Cook (undertaking), 1924 (Box-folder 21 / 1)
    - Mergenthaler Lynotype Company case (includes statement of case, mortgages, satisfactions of mortgages, etc.), 1917-1929 (Box-folder 21 / 2)
    - A.L. Smith, Trustee vs. A.B. Cook (foreclosure which resulted in sale of his cattle), 1928 (Box-folder 21 / 3)
    - Notebook re court cases, ca. 1895-1898 (Box-folder 21 / 4)
  - Financial Records
    - Bills, invoices, etc. [sampled], 1893-1928 (Box-folder 21 / 5-13)
    - Bills for services: Gunn, Rasch and Hall, attorneys, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 21 / 14)
    - Bills due, 1921, 1923 (Box-folder 21 / 15)
    - Checkstubs, cancelled checks, bank statements, etc., 1886-1901 (Box-folder 21 / 16-21)
    - Checkstubs, cancelled checks, bank statements, etc., 1900-1928 (Box-folder 22 / 1-7)
    - Checkstubs, cancelled checks, bank statements, etc., 1911-1928 (Box-folder 23 / 1-5)
    - Financial statements, 1909-1928 (Box-folder 23 / 6)
    - Fire insurance, 1909, 1914 (Box-folder 23 / 7)
    - Inventory: Helena warehouse, 1913, n.d. (Box-folder 23 / 8)
    - Investments, 1916 (Box-folder 23 / 9)
    - Life insurance, 1889, 1914-1927 (Box-folder 23 / 10)
    - Liquor inventories, 1918 (Box-folder 23 / 11)
    - Promissory notes, 1890-1927 (Box-folder 23 / 12)
    - Receipts: Masonic and fraternal orders, 1888-1920 (Box-folder 23 / 13)
    - Receipts: social clubs, 1889-1926 (Box-folder 23 / 14)
    - Taxes: City of Helena, 1890-1927 (Box-folder 23 / 15)
    - Taxes: Lewis and Clark County, 1888-1928 (Box-folder 23 / 16)
    - Taxes: Park County (re property at Cooke City), 1890-1919 (Box-folder 23 / 17)
    - Taxes: certificates of redemption of property sold for taxes, 1899, 1901 1927-1928 (Box-folder 23 / 18)
  - Legal Documents
    - Affidavit as candidate for Republican National Committee, 1924 (Box-folder 23 / 19)
    - Bill for appointment of a Deputy State Auditor (SB 21), n.d. (Box-folder 23 / 20)
    - Bills of sale, 1918, 1928 (Box-folder 23 / 21)
    - Cooke City property, 1886-1891, 1911 (Box-folder 23 / 22)
    - James Gorman Estate (Tacoma, Wash.), 1891-1893 (Box-folder 23 / 23)
    - Helena property: Brooke Addition [map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 1], 1890 (Box-folder 23 / 24)
    - Helena property: Northern Pacific #1 Addition, 1887-1901 (Box-folder 23 / 25)
    - Helena property: Northern Pacific #2 Addition, 1889-1902 (Box-folder 23 / 26)
    - Helena property: Thompson Placer Claim (West Lawrence Street), 1889-1895, 1918 (Box-folder 23 / 27)
    - Mining claims, 1894-1897 (Box-folder 23 / 28)
    - Will, 1916 (Box-folder 23 / 29)
  - Maps
    - List of maps in oversize folders (Box-folder 23 / 30)
  - Reports
    - James S. Cunningham report on geology of P. Burns Coal Mines, Ltd. (Sheep Creek, Alta.), 1919 (Box-folder 24 / 1)
    - R.H. Ewart, "Geological report of Genou Fold of the Sweet Grass Arch", 1921 (Box-folder 24 / 2)
    - C.P. Hill, "Commercial report on the necessity of more smelters of silver, lead, zinc and antimony ores mined in Canada, as viewed from a Canadian standpoint", 1915 (Box-folder 24 / 3)
    - John F. Stevens, "Alaskan Railways: Contract vs. Direct Government Work", 1915 (Box-folder 24 / 4)
  - Subject Files
    - Boat, 1917 (Box-folder 24 / 5)
    - A.B. Cook home, Townsend (includes specifications for original house and for additions and alterations [blueprints in OVERSIZE FOLDER 2], 1915, 1919 (Box-folder 24 / 6)
    - Lake McDonald cottage, 1926 (Box-folder 24 / 7)
    - Land (includes Indian Creek placers, Beartooth Ranch, etc.) [Maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1915-1916 (Box-folder 24 / 8)
    - Mines: Beaver Creek Mining Company list of stock certificates, 1917 (Box-folder 24 / 9)
    - Mines: Black Friday Mine (Radersburg, Mont.), 1910 (Box-folder 24 / 10)
    - Mines: British Columbia, ca. 1911 (Box-folder 24 / 11)
    - Mines: Cataract Placer Claim (Jefferson County, Mont.: report by E. Gybons Spilsbury), 1887 (Box-folder 24 / 12)
    - Mines: Clark Fork River [map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1923 (Box-folder 24 / 13)
    - Mines: Colin Campbell Lode (Lake and Park counties, Colo.), ca. 1901 (Box-folder 24 / 14)
    - Mines: Columbian group of quartz mines (York, Mont., includes Golden Messenger and Dandy), ca. 1900 (Box-folder 24 / 15)
    - Mines: Federal Zinc and Lead Company (Gaspe County., Que., includes report by Walter Harvey Weed), 1918-1926 (Box-folder 24 / 16)
    - Mines: Gravelly Range placers (Madison County, Mont., includes report by F.B. Turner on Rubylyn and Sapphire claims), 1899, n.d. (Box-folder 24 / 17)
    - Mines: Hudson Bay mining claims (Salma, B.C., includes report by R.K. Neill), n.d. (Box-folder 24 / 18)
    - Mines: Josephine Mine (Rimini, Mont., includes report by P. Knabe), 1892 (Box-folder 24 / 19)
    - Mines: Keystone and King Mining and Milling Company (Spring Gulch Mining District, Missoula County, Mont., includes report by J.W. Hamilton) (Box-folder 24 / 20)
    - Mines: T.H. McFadden claims (Thompson Mining District, Mont.), 1885-1889 (Box-folder 24 / 21)
    - Mines: Montana-Idaho Mines Corporation, 1927 (Box-folder 24 / 22)
    - Mines: Montana, Pony and Pay Rock claims (near Libby, Mont.) [map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3] (Box-folder 24 / 23)
    - Mines: Neihart area, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 24 / 24)
    - Mines: New Jersey Blue Mine (Butte, Mont., includes report by Michael Cooney) [Map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1890 (Box-folder 24 / 25)
    - Mines: Prize Mine (Granite Butte, Powell County, Mont., includes report and map by J. McConnell), 1894 (Box-folder 24 / 26)
    - Mines: Red Mountain Consolidated Mining Company (Rimini, Mont.) [Map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1926 (Box-folder 24 / 27)
    - Mines: Ruby Gulch Mining Company (Phillips County, Mont., includes reports by Melvin S. Patterson, Marcus L. Hurley, William R. Price), 1927 (Box-folder 24 / 28)
    - Mines: Union Mining Company (Unionville, Mont., stockholder list) [Map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1901 (Box-folder 24 / 29)
    - Mines: miscellaneous (includes Mineral County mines, Davis Placer report, Butte West Side Mines Company prospectus, Hazel Mining Company prospectus, Ohio and Climax production, notes) [Map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 3], 1897-1924 (Box-folder 24 / 30)
    - Mining letters, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 24 / 31)
    - New Day Oil Company drilling, 1927 (Box-folder 24 / 32)
    - United Copper Aetna deal, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 24 / 33)
    - Western Gas Construction Company (includes Loomis Gas and Electric Company brochures), 1889 (Box-folder 24 / 34)
    - Wyoming, Salt Lake and California Railway, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 24 / 35)
  - Miscellany
    - American Kennel Club (AKC) registration form, including list of dog breeds, n.d. (Box-folder 25 / 1)
    - Art (pencil sketch, probably of Mary and Jesus, by unknown artist) (Box-folder 25 / 2)
    - Boone and Crockett Club membership list [A-H only], 1892-1926 (Box-folder 25 / 3)
    - Broadwater County annual financial statements, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 25 / 4)
    - Broadwater County precinct list, 1920 (Box-folder 25 / 5)
    - Cartoon re A.B. Cook "What Big Business Tried to Do", n.d. (Box-folder 25 / 6)
    - P.J. Coleman address to Farmers Elevator Association, 1926 (Box-folder 25 / 7)
    - Helena Builders and Manufacturers Exchange constitution and bylaws, 1891 (Box-folder 25 / 8)
    - Letterheads, n.d. (Box-folder 25 / 9)
    - List of lands under Billings Ditch (Box-folder 25 / 10)
    - Memorandum books (Box-folder 25 / 11)
    - Montana Club annual report and membership list [incomplete set], 1894-1922 (Box-folder 25 / 12)
    - National Arbitration and Peace Congress dinner program, 1907 (Box-folder 25 / 13)
    - Pioneers of Eastern Montana constitution and bylaws, 1903 (Box-folder 25 / 14)
    - "Report of the Anti-Saloon League of Montana", 1924 (Box-folder 25 / 15)
    - Sawyer Stores, Inc. prospectus, 1926 (Box-folder 25 / 16)
    - Taxpayers organization brochures and flyers, 1921, n.d. (Box-folder 25 / 17)
    - Wedding congratulations, 1908 (Box-folder 25 / 18)
    - Willow Creek Oils, Ltd. prospectus, 1914 (Box-folder 25 / 19)
    - Miscellaneous (includes Cook Coal Company stock certificate, Montana Drug Company balance sheet, Montana Mining Company equipment for sale, address by Cornelius F. Kelley before Montana Bankers Association, Collins Land Company brochure, poems, etc.), 1897-1927 (Box-folder 25 / 20)
- A.B. Cook Estate
  - General Correspondence
    - A-M (correspondents include American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association, C. Dunkel, Walter J. Hill, Illinois Steel Bridge Company, The Jockey Club, James H. Johnston, Arthur T. McIntosh and Company, McIntyre Ranching Company, Hazel Alsterberg Mitchell, Montana Life Insurance Company, Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company), 1928-1930 (Box-folder 25 / 21)
    - R-W (correspondents include John Reagor, Seattle National Bank, State Bank of Chicago, J.D. Watson, T.B. Weir), 1928-1930 (Box-folder 25 / 22)
  - Court Papers
    - Notice of probate; creditor's claim; petition for sale of personal property, 1928, 1930 (Box-folder 25 / 23)
  - Financial Records
    - Checkstubs, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 25 / 24)
- A.B. Cook Stock Farms
  - Court Papers
    - A.B. Cook testimony in John Doughty case (re theft of Cotswold sheep), ca. 1921 (Box-folder 26 / 1)
    - Meagher County water rights case (lists Confederate Creek water rights), 1890 (Box-folder 26 / 2)
  - Employment Records
    - Employment agency referrals: Coe's Employment Agency (Helena, Mont.), 1918-1920 (Box-folder 26 / 3)
    - Employment agency referrals: Kain's Employment Agency (Helena, Mont.), 1921-1924 (Box-folder 26 / 4)
    - Employment agency referrals: Randall's Employment Agency (Billings, Mont.), 1923-1928 (Box-folder 26 / 5)
    - Employment agency referrals: Montana Employment Agency; Montana Labor Office (Charlie Rustad, Great Falls, Mont.), 1922-1923 (Box-folder 26 / 6)
    - Employment agency referrals: Tonn's Employment Agency (Helena, Mont.), 1925-1927 (Box-folder 26 / 7)
    - Employment agency referrals (miscellaneous), 1918-1928 (Box-folder 26 / 8)
    - Employment applications (includes some biographical material), 1926-1928 (Box-folder 26 / 9-11)
    - Monthly labor reports (gives labor cost of each operation), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 26 / 12)
    - Payrolls/time sheets/time books (includes Bedford, Dunleavy, Rorvig and Sheep ranches), 1915-1922 (Box-folder 26 / 13-18)
    - Payrolls/time sheets/time books (includes Bedford, Dunleavy, Rorvig and Sheep ranches), 1923-1954 (Box-folder 27 / 1-3)
    - Payrolls/time sheets/time books: carpenters includes A.B. Cook house, Bedford, Dunleavy, Rorvig and Sheep ranches), 1917-1921 (Box-folder 27 / 4-5)
    - Payroll: ditch work, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 27 / 6)
  - Financial Records
    - Accounts, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 7-8)
    - Bank statements, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 28 / 1)
    - Bills, invoices, etc., 1925-1930 (Box-folder 28 / 2-3)
    - Cash book and voucher register, 1920 (Volume Vol. 1)
    - Checkstubs, 1927-1933 (Box-folder 28 / 4-7)
    - Commissary account books, 1917, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 28 / 8-9)
    - Grocery lists, 1923, n.d. (Box-folder 28 / 10)
    - C.D. Hall account, 1928 (Box-folder 28 / 11)
    - Hay scale receipts, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 28 / 12)
    - Axel Holmstrom accounts, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 28 / 13)
    - Hotel accounts, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 28 / 14)
    - Inventories (include Dunleavy, Bedford, Rorvig, Luppold, and Sheep ranches), 1913-1933 (Box-folder 29 / 1-12)
    - Monthly financial statements, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 29 / 13)
    - Promissory notes, 1919, 1925 (Box-folder 29 / 14)
    - Requisitions, 1920-1924 (Box-folder 29 / 15-18)
    - Show cattle expenses and winnings, 1919-1921, n.d. (Box-folder 30 / 1)
    - Taxes: Broadwater County, 1914-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 2)
    - Taxes: Meagher County, 1918-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 3)
    - Taxes on shipped cattle, 1918-1925 (Box-folder 30 / 4)
    - Trial balance sheet, May 1919 (Box-folder 30 / 5)
    - Wool warehouse receipts, 1916 (Box-folder 30 / 6)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstract of title and deeds: Bedford Townsite, 1882-1919 (Box-folder 30 / 7)
    - Canadian customs forms for exhibit cattle, 1919 (Box-folder 30 / 8)
    - Chattel mortgages on cattle (includes correspondence, lists, etc.), 1923-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 9)
    - Dunleavy Ranch, 1912 (Box-folder 30 / 10)
    - Axel Holmstrom, 1918 (Box-folder 30 / 11)
    - Livestock contracts with railroads, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 12)
    - Mortgages, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 13)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Land Dept., 1916-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 14)
    - Jay Rathbun, 1912-1923 (Box-folder 30 / 15)
    - Nick Rorvig, 1916 (Box-folder 30 / 16)
    - Sheriff's sales, 1923, 1926, 1928 (Box-folder 30 / 17)
    - Springville Townsite, 1894-1912 (Box-folder 30 / 18)
    - State lands, 1919, 1928 (Box-folder 30 / 19)
    - White Sulphur Springs property, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 30 / 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-1928 (Box-folder 30 / 21)
  - Maps
    - Maps of ranch property [includes OVERSIZE FOLDER 4] (Box-folder 30 / 22)
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes electing officers, 1919 (Box-folder 30 / 23)
  - Printed Material
    - A.B. Cook's Herefords: a select sale offering of fifty-two head (sale catalog), 1920 (Box-folder 30 / 24)
  - Production Records
    - American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association: certificates of entry [chronologically arranged], 1901-1933 (Box-folder Cardbx / 1)
    - American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association: registration stub books, 1911-1922 (Box-folder 31 / 1-3)
    - American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association: registration stub books, 1924-1930 (Box-folder 32 / 1-4)
    - American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association: transfer stub books (sales of cattle), 1909-1923 (Box-folder 32 / 5-7)
    - American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association: transfer stub books (sales of cattle), 1923-1928 (Box-folder 33 / 1-2)
    - American Rambouillet Sheep Breeders Association: registrations, 1922 (Box-folder 33 / 3)
    - Breeding and birth records: Hereford cattle, 1918-1921 (Box-folder 33 / 4-7)
    - Breeding and birth records: Hereford cattle, 1922-1926 (Box-folder 34 / 1-3)
    - Breeding registers: Hereford cattle, 1914-1924 (Box-folder 34 / 4-6)
    - Breeding registers: Holstein dairy cattle, 1912-1926 (Box-folder 34 / 7)
    - Calves dropped, 1908-1925, 1928 (Box-folder 34 / 8-12)
    - Calves dropped: White Sulphur Springs, 1918-1923 (Box-folder 35 / 1-2)
    - Canadian Hereford Breeders Association: pedigree registrations, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 35 / 3)
    - Cattle lists, 1910-1928 (Box-folder 35 / 4-11)
    - Holstein-Friesian Association registrations [additional Holstein records in CardBx 1], 1928-1929 (Box-folder 35 / 12)
    - Horse pedigrees and lists [additional Belgian Horse records in Cardbx 1; pedigree of Rogon in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1910-1917 (Box-folder 35 / 13)
    - Lamb sales, 1919 (Box-folder 35 / 14)
    - National Duroc-Jersey Record Association registrations (pigs), 1924, 1926 (Box-folder 35 / 15)
    - Pedigree cards: Hereford cattle [unsorted] (Box-folder Cardbx / 1-2)
    - Pedigree cards: Hereford cattle, A-W, 1902-1913 (Box-folder 36 / 1)
    - Pedigree books and sheets: Hereford cattle [various arrangements], 1904-1923 (Box-folder 36 / 2-5)
    - Sheep at shearing, 1917-1923 (Box-folder 36 / 6)
  - Subject Files
    - Accredited herd papers (re tuberculosis-free certification), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 36 / 7)
    - Advertising, 1921-1928 (Box-folder 36 / 8-9)
    - Belgian horses (includes Major d'Appel), 1925-1928 (Box-folder 36 / 10)
    - Brands, 1912-1927 (Box-folder 36 / 11)
    - Cattle dealers and breeders, 1913-1921 (Box-folder 36 / 12)
    - Cesspool design, 1925 (Box-folder 37 / 1)
    - Chickens (also includes turkeys and geese), 1918-1922 (Box-folder 37 / 2)
    - Combine sale, 1927 (Box-folder 37 / 3)
    - Dogs, 1915-1927 (Box-folder 37 / 4)
    - Fairs, expositions, and sales (re Cook's entry of Hereford show herd at United States and Canada fairs, includes lists, prizes, expenses) [certificates and posters in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1916-1926 (Box-folder 37 / 5-15)
    - Fairs, expositions, and sales (continued), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 38 / 1-4)
    - Feeding experiments, 1925 (Box-folder 38 / 5)
    - Fencing, 1917-1926 (Box-folder 38 / 6)
    - Fire insurance [map of layout of buildings at ranch in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1917, 1927 (Box-folder 38 / 7)
    - Fish and game (re stocking of trout in Sheep Creek, migratory bird refuges, etc.), 1924 (Box-folder 38 / 8)
    - Grinders (re grain and feed grinders), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 38 / 9)
    - Havey Brothers ranch, 1922 (Box-folder 38 / 10)
    - Hay and straw, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 38 / 11)
    - Holstein dairy cattle, 1916, 1924 (Box-folder 38 / 12)
    - Horse hitch systems, n.d. (Box-folder 38 / 13)
    - Irrigation: map of proposed irrigation canal by John H. Farmer, n.d. (Box-folder OVFD / 5)
    - Irrigation: Charles W. Helmick plans for diversion of Missouri River near Dunleavy ranch [maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1920-1925 (Box-folder 38 / 14)
    - Irrigation: Don Mumbrue re Bedford Ditch, 1921 (Box-folder 38 / 15)